PERSONAL INFO



Phone: (+52) 444 1192990



E-mail: luispablo2098@hotmail.com



in Linkedin: Luis Pablo Rocha

A background in programming, web, software engineering, operating systems, and other areas of technology; with a bachelor's degree focused on projects, I worked in many teams using agile work and development methodologies; building skills such as responsibility, effective communication, problem solving and organization.

EXPERIENCE

QUINI

REACT NATIVE & FIGMA | AUGUST 2023 - CURRENT

- Building a soccer betting app to keep track of your sports bets with your friends using React Native Framework.
- Design and creation of brand identity, logo and screens, based on basic UI/UX design patterns, using tools such as Figma and Illustrator.

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

DELIVERY SLP

SQL SERVER & POSTGRESQL | MAR 2021 - JUN 2021

- Database design: entity-relational model.
- Database access control and use of simple triggers.
- · Developed a packet transport system in C# and Java with SQL queries to databases
 - Generate shipping orders, historical records, and role-based access control.

PREDACAD

POSTGRESQL, ANGULAR & SCRUM FRAMEWORK | FEB 2021 - JUN 2021

- Interface design following basic UX/UI principles with Figma, Ilustrator and Photoshop
- Recollection and pre-processing data (student academic records) using data sheets [Excel].
- Developed and programmed a web system (data interpretation) that predicts the probability that a student will pass a subject using data mining techniques. (Web API's with JSON)

HARDWARE STORE: ONLINE ORDERS

LARAVEL, BOOTSTRAP & MYSQL | JAN 2020 - JUN 2020

- Developed a website to order from a Hardware store using web technologies such as HTM and Javascript.
- Creation of the database, normalization, and SQL statements.
- Use of the model-view-controller (MVC) architecture pattern
- The administrator had the possibility to add, edit, and delete products to a department of the hardware store. As well as control (status) of orders placed by customers.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CUSTOMER SERVICE, ADMINISTRATION & COMPUTING | FERRE STA. RITA OFFICE 365 & CFDI 4.0 | DEC 2022 - CURRENT | PART TIME JOB

- · Electronic billing procedures and keeping track of accounts receivable and transactions.
- · Customer service counter.
- · Creation of price lists in Excel.
- Processes from inventory management to the point-of-sale.

FRONT END FREELANCER | INDOOR MX HTML, JAVASCRIPT & CSS | JUN 2020 - DEC 2020

- Design and development of a static web page for food delivery using web technologies. https://indoormx.com/
- Help the company to make itself known and to be contacted.

COURSES & ACTIVITIES

- COURSE | React Professional Course | 10-Hours | October 2023 | Online
- COURSE | React Native Course | 4-Hours | October 2023 | Online
- COURSE | CCNA Routing and Switching: Introduction to Networks | CISCO Networking Academy | 2020
- COURSE | Master in JavaScript Frameworks: Learn Angular y React | Udemy | 2020 | Online

LANGUAGES

- Spanish (Native)
- English TOEFL B2 High Intermediate (2023)
- French and German A1

SKILLS

- Database design and administration [PostgreSQL, SQL Server & MySQL)
- C, C# & Java
- HTML, CSS & JavaScript
- Python (Elementary)
- Angular & React

EDUCATION

COMPUTER ENGINEER

Universidad Autónoma de San Luis Potosí Facultad de Ingeniería Aug 2016-Feb 2023

- Linux [Ubuntu] & Windows (Beginner)
- NoSQL [MongoDB] (Beginner)
- Flutter (Beginner)
- Software Version Control [GitHub)
- Project Management Software [Jira]
- Photoshop and Illustrator